[theme music playing]
THE RED IN OUR LIVES
[muffled traffic]
[groans, smacks lips]
[grunting softly]
Uh, Haru?
[sniffs]
[groans softly]
Huh?
[melancholy music playing]
[breath trembles]
[inhales sharply]
[heart beating]
[gasping]
[whimpering]
[Legoshi] I'm dreaming, right?
This has gotta be a dream.
Haru...
[sobbing]
This hurts.
This is real.
You idiot!
Why... Why?
[strangled howl]
[inhales sharply]
Haru... Haru.
Haru.
Haru...
[echoing voice] That's how it should be.
Huh?
[shadowy figure] You've buried
your feelings ever since you were a kid.
You've lived quietly in the darkness.
[Legoshi] Hold on.
I thought I had locked you away.
[shadowy figure] Well, it turns out Melon
was kind enough to open the door for me.
[Legoshi gasps]
Those flames
burning deep within his eyes...
It's what I was afraid of.
[sobbing]
[shadowy figure] Don't turn away.
Face yourself.
What feeling creeps in?
Sadness? Or is it frustration?
Or is it neither?
It's your instinct, alive and well.
No! [sobbing]
How could I? What have I done?
I'll never see her again.
[continues sobbing]
[door opens]
[Haru] Oh, sorry about the mess.
I was going to clean that when I got back.
Huh?
[sighs] I've gotta be more careful
with tomato juice.
I'm better at spilling it
than drinking it.
H... Haru?
Tomato juice?
[sniffs]
Was I too shocked to use my nose?
[Haru] What is it? What's wrong?
Hey, are you okay?
You didn't have a nightmare, did you?
It was a nightmare, and it felt so real.
It was frightening.
I'm just glad I'm awake.
- You're so warm.
- [exhales worriedly]
How about, um, some breakfast?
[chuckles lightly]
We have yogurt and bread.
So, which one?
We've got aloe or strawberry.
- [Legoshi sighs]
- Well, for me, I like strawberry.
[Legoshi exhales heavily]
I'm so grateful.
[giggles] Too slow. You get aloe. Here!
[Legoshi] Outside of my nightmare,
I guess we're really pretty lucky.
Come and get it!
[Legoshi] If I have this dream
of eating her...
I can't imagine
Haru hasn't dreamt of me doing it.
And yet here she is,
with her yogurt and bread,
happy to have breakfast with me,
like it's just what we do.
You've got all our weight
on your shoulders.
Just you. But because of that, we work.
- Listen, Haru!
- [Haru exclaims]
[gentle music playing]
You and me...
I think you and I should get married.
I wanna live with you. Maybe have kids.
And no matter what nightmares pop up,
I know we can handle it.
And I wanna have yogurt
every single day with you.
I mean, don't we deserve happiness?
I wanna be happy with you.
Uh... yeah.
Okay. Well, then, I have a request for us.
[Legoshi] Anything.
I wanna see the Festival of the Meteor.
And I wanna go with you.
The festival?
Well, we couldn't do it last year.
And when we go,
let's light a candle together.
Make a promise.
[Legoshi] She will be my wife.
Before that, though,
I made a promise to Mr. Yahya.
Where are you, Melon?
[music swells forebodingly]
KING OF BEASTS
[Free sighs]
You know, Melon, he, uh...
he never even bothered
to learn Hino's name.
And in Melon's eyes, gang members are
nothing but weak little pawns.
HERE LIES HINO
[Agata] Damn, Hino...
You deserved better. You deserved a death
worthy of a lion's mane.
[clippers buzzing]
Hey! What are you doing?
I haven't earned my mane, have I?
I'm following Melon
even after Hino was killed.
The king of beasts, my ass!
- Stop! Come on!
- [all struggling]
I don't deserve this mane!
- Stop! Just stop!
- Get off me! Just let me do this!
We're right here with you!
- We know this isn't easy!
- Remember what he said!
He said, since you were born a male lion,
it falls upon you to become
a king of beasts worthy of your mane.
Exactly. You take care of it
until you earn it,
and that takes time. And you know that.
But Hino... our Hino...
At this rate, my mane will just sit
on the head of a pretender!
[inhales shakily]
How am I supposed to ever forgive Melon?
He'll never be Shishi-Gumi!
[Victor] Are you gonna
take him down, then?
And you think you're up for that?
Let's say you do.
When a turf war breaks out,
what are we supposed to do without a boss?
Meat Appreciation Day...
How great would it be
if we got Louis back?
Yeah, that'd be nice.
Louis, huh... He treated us
like the kings of beasts that we are.
That was great.
I'll admit, Louis was the man.
But nothing lasts forever.
Well, if we asked nicely,
he might come back.
- Maybe if we bowed our heads in respect--
- [Legoshi] No way! You can't do that!
- What?
- The hell?
[Legoshi] Oh.
- [Free] Looky here. I remember you.
- [guns cock]
Looks like you're still alive.
What are you doing here?
Forget what dyin' feels like?
[Legoshi] You gotta listen.
Hear me out. I just...
just want to ask something.
[lion snarls]
I want Melon,
and I thought you all could help.
- And why would you think that?
- I want to catch him.
Unless I'm wrong,
sounds like you all want Melon gone.
If we could work toge-- Whoa!
Us following a wolf? You must be nuts!
[Legoshi] I'm not asking you to follow me.
Now, wait. We seem to have the same goal.
Louis is my senior,
but I don't think he should be your boss.
What? What do you mean,
Louis is your senior?
- What are you blabbing about?
- In high school he was my senior.
[Jimma] Huh?
I don't care who you are to Louis.
[Victor grunts]
Yeah, sure, Melon's a problem for us,
but we're not desperate enough
to turn to a canine!
Don't worry, pup.
We can solve this on our own.
And now, since those canine ears
hear so well,
now we gotta make sure you stay dead!
[Legoshi grunting]
[Legoshi panting]
Use your heads.
You think Louis will forgive you
if you kill me?
Pretty confident, I see.
I'll admit, kid, you got balls.
But losing any more of our lion's pride
ain't on the table.
This time when you die, you'll stay dead.
[growls]
- [Mayor] The Zoolympics.
- [triumphant music playing]
[Mayor] All manner of species
coming together
to showcase a wide range
of special abilities.
It's an event
that transcends our differences,
where we can exist in peace
and mutually appreciate our achievements.
It embodies our slogan, "Live Together,"
my vision for co-existence and prosperity.
I'm currently considering the prospect of
bringing the Zoolympics to our fine city.
Interesting. I've heard
the costs can be astronomical.
Oftentimes, cities withdraw their bids.
In spite of that,
I believe there's an opportunity there.
As for the costs, I'm a little more
optimistic in that regard.
Of course, that depends on Mr. Ogma
chairing the bidding committee.
MAYOR
[Louis] Something seems off here.
Does Father have some kind of a plan?
[Mayor] On top of that,
I feel we have something special
we can bring to the table.
[Louis] Uh... raw meat?
[Mayor] Lab-cultured meat.
Oh, yeah, I vaguely recall
hearing about that.
[Mayor] Using cultured muscle cells,
this was artificially created
through the wonders of science,
meaning no one had to die for this
and it can be consumed ethically.
[Louis] Its resemblance to the real thing
is remarkable.
[Mayor] It tastes like regular meat
and has the same nutrients.
I didn't know its development
was this far along.
Apparently, it's almost ready for release.
[Louis] So then...
It's no secret some athletes have been
eating meat and getting away with it,
and that's, of course,
a regrettable aspect.
Agreed.
So, then, what if the solution is
offering this meat to those same athletes?
I'm sure carnivores across the board
would have no problem with that.
And with that, its nutrition
would give them the edge
for record-breaking performance.
For Horns Pharmaceuticals and Ogura Foods,
it's the perfect advertising opportunity.
[Louis] So, Azuki's father's company,
working with Horns Pharmaceuticals?
This smells fishy.
- [Louis gasps]
- [Mayor] So here's where you come in.
We have decided that you should serve
as our ambassador for the bid.
[Louis] What?
The younger crowds respect you.
You have influence.
You're seen as a future Beastar
by the community.
[Louis exhales tensely]
Uh, Father?
I think it's clear.
I understand.
- [phone buzzes]
- Oh.
[Mayor] Oh, look at how your antlers
have grown.
KITTY:
WE'VE GOT THE WOLF
Like father, like son.
I'm looking forward to working together.
All right, let's start
the first read-through. We ready?
[all affirm]
[Juno] Pina, you really know
how to get under my skin,
but for the sake of the play,
I can look past that.
[Kibi] "One thousand years ago,
an era when herbivores and carnivores
lived together in harmony,
without division..."
"Laila and the others went out
to gather fruit."
"It's been seven sunrises
since they left."
"They don't usually take this long."
"Don't worry, it's Laila.
She's definitely fine."
"Laila enters from stage right."
"Everyone, don't worry. We've returned!"
"On our way back
we were attacked by Jaguars,
but with these fangs, and with my claws--"
"Everyone, don't worry. We've returned!"
"On our way back we were attacked
by Jaguars, but with--"
Whoa, hold it, hang on!
What are you doing?
Stick to the lines that are yours.
I understand the concept.
I was just thinking how I would play it.
Huh?
The character is a strong leader
with a quiet confidence.
Wouldn't it be striking
if they're nonchalant about this violence?
- Oh, yeah, I see what you mean.
- Yeah, but--
Okay, you're only here for one reason.
You're perfect for the role of Garan.
That's right. Let's remember
the illustrations of herbivores
from the time period this play is set in.
The horned sheep is very iconic.
With you in that role, we bring in
the authentic flavor of that era.
[Pina] Mmm, yeah, I hear you
about that ancient stuff.
Listen. Wouldn't me playing a carnivore
be more intriguing?
[Kibi] You're saying...
Imagine this. We shake things up.
The carnivores and herbivores
swap their roles.
- Huh?
- Hmmm?
Isn't that... Isn't that
a little bit out there? [chuckles]
Ugh! Classic behavior
of an egotistical narcissist!
Won't that just confuse the audience?
I get that, but we could find some ways
to make it more clear,
like using wardrobe to spell it out.
Not bad. Maybe we could dress
the herbivores in green,
and then the carnivores could wear orange.
Isn't an aspect of acting
the valiant attempt
to portray something you are not?
- Well, yeah, you do have a point...
- Now, wait just a second!
You've got some nerve! You want to steal
the role of Laila from me.
Besides, I don't know the first thing
about playing an herbivore.
That's perfect, then.
You can challenge yourself.
Playing Laila is already
challenging enough!
Has it even occurred to you
that you don't understand
the carnivore experience?
Let me ask you, Juno, have you ever caused
harm to an herbivore before?
What?
Have you ever hurt one, or eaten one?
- Anything like that?
- [Juno] No, of course I haven't.
So when your character does those things,
you're using your imagination?
Yeah, but that's not the same.
[Pina] I understand, Juno.
You just want the role that shows you
in your best light, am I right?
A role with just enough drama,
and monologues,
so you can soak up the spotlight
as the glamorous protagonist.
You're wrong! It's about the play.
I just want to serve the work, and play
the role that I'm the best fit for.
I believe in you. That's why I think
you should play an herbivore.
You wanna be a Beastar, right?
- Just think, looks good on a résumé...
- My résumé?
Can you imagine it?
You playing a weak herbivore
who can only survive by acting tough.
I can almost see it now.
- That could work.
- Yeah.
There's nothing wrong
with playing it safe.
At least it would be easier.
[Kibi] Yeah,
but now that I think about it,
Pina might be on to something.
I have to say, it sounds good.
Pina's got some great ideas.
Sounds like it can make the theme
really stand out.
Also, it kind of connects back to Adler.
Isn't it true that Adler originally had
herbivores playing predators
to reinforce his ideas?
Well, I must admit, it would make
the dual performance more meaningful,
- and much more unique...
- You aren't being serious!
[Pina laughs]
Does the prospect of this frighten you?
Are you worried because you don't think
you can pull it off?
What? I can't believe you.
What makes you think stepping into
the role of a carnivore is easy?
I actually think
it'll be quite the challenge,
one I know I'm ready for.
Well, all right. I'll do it.
I'll play Garan, then!
You'll be sorry, 'cause I'll do it
better than you ever could.
Nice! That's the spirit.
[Juno sighs]
What am I getting myself into?
[line ringing]
[Louis] I'm here.
So, how's the hostage?
I wondered if you'd come.
You've got some nerve.
What part of threatening me
sounded like a good idea?
Tell me another way
we could have gotten you to show up.
You know it's true.
You won't even pick up the phone.
Enough. Just bring out the wolf.
If you hurt them,
then we're gonna have a problem.
[Louis stifles exclamation]
You're kidding me. You're the wolf?
So, uh, hello... Oh!
[Louis sighs exasperatedly]
What the hell are you doing here?
[chuckles awkwardly] Let me guess.
Did you think it was Juno they took?
[Louis sighs]
So, tell me what happened.
I need to talk to Melon,
and I figured they knew where he was.
If I recall, you were done with Melon.
Isn't that right?
Yeah, I was, but, well...
if I can catch Melon, they'll erase
my carnivore criminal record.
If I don't, I won't be able to marry Haru.
So your bright idea was to get them
to tell you where Melon was?
You know they could have killed you.
Well, "could have" almost became "did,"
although they did say
if you asked them, they'd tell me.
The way he was saying it was that
you'd show up if it was for him.
- What?
- [laughing nervously] Well...
I know you cut ties with the Shishi-Gumi,
so this is on me. I'm sorry.
Uh, but still, though,
think you could do me a solid?
Jeez...
Even if you caught this mixed maniac,
that's no guarantee
of a happily ever after.
Right. I'll keep that in mind.
[footsteps echoing heavily]
I'm here, as you asked.
Tell him where Melon is.
Make good on your end.
[Dolph] Sure, we're gonna tell him,
on one condition.
Which is...
Louis...
we want you to take up the mantle again.
Come back and be our Shishi-Gumi boss.
- Stop it. That's not fair!
- [Dolph] Quiet!
- We'll follow your orders if you lead us.
- [Legoshi] This wasn't our agreement.
So if you want us to help this wolf...
[Legoshi] You said if he asked,
that would be enough.
- Shut it!
- [Legoshi] Sorry.
That's all we ask.
- [inhales deeply] So we're clear?
- [moody jazz music playing]
You'll help him if I take the reins?
Respectfully... We're begging you.
[Legoshi] I've never seen
anything like this.
Look at him.
A deer that is able to command lions.
I refuse.
- Huh?
- But... why not?
[Louis sighs softly]
Ibuki died because of me...
and because I said
I would step down as boss.
[Free sighs]
[Louis] I can't forget that.
He gave his life. He died
to protect the Shishi-Gumi's pride.
And if I returned,
his death would be for nothing.
Therefore...
I can't return.
I can never be your boss again.
[footsteps echoing heavily]
Louis... [sighs softly]
I'm sorry. I hope you understand.
[Legoshi sighs]
[Free] Hey.
Huh?
So, about Melon...
Apparently he's called "Professor"
in polite society.
Oh.
"Professor"?
[closing theme song playing]